Howard Bond Negatives
Howard Bond Negatives
1974-2005
Bond, Howard.
2 linear ft.
Negatives for 17 of Bond's 23 limited edition portfolios.
5135321
Biographical History
Howard Bond is an American photographer. His photographs are in the collections of more than 30 museums in the United States and Europe, and he has had over 60 one-man and 40 group exhibitions. The recipient of a Michigan Council for the Arts Creative Artist Grant, he has published 2 books and 23 limited edition portfolios of prints. His educational activities include 24 years of writing for Photo Techniques magazine and 34 years of teaching workshops that have been attended by over 2000 photographers from 5 continents. [Information taken from Howard Bond's website.]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Howard Bond Negatives consists of negatives for 17 of Bond's 23 limited edition portfolios. Many are accompanied by Bond's extensive notes and annotations on subject, technique, etc. The negatives have been removed from their glassine envelopes for preservation, but the envelopes have been preserved. Each envelope precedes all the negatives originally contained within it.
In some cases a pair of negatives will be found taped together; this appears to have been deliberate on the part of the photographer, and they should not be separated.
Arrangement of the Collection
As received from donor.
Related Material
has copies of Bond's limited edition portfolios in its Rare Books holdings. Please refer to to locate these items.
Subject and Genre Headings
Photography; Bond, Howard.; Cathedrals -- England -- Pictorial works.; Nature photography.; Landscape photographers -- United States.; Photographers -- United States.; Photography, Abstract.; Photography, Artistic.; Alps, Swiss (Switzerland) -- Pictorial works.; Arizona -- Pictorial works.; Greece -- Pictorial works.; Hocking Hills (Ohio) -- Pictorial works.; Huron River (Oakland County-Monroe County, Mich.) -- Pictorial works.; Kings Canyon National Park (Calif.) -- Pictorial works.; Kyklades (Greece) -- Pictorial works.; New Zealand -- Pictorial works.; Ontario -- Pictorial works.; San Juan Mountains (Colo. and N.M.) -- Pictorial works.; Utah -- Pictorial works.; West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works.; White River (Colo. and Utah) -- Pictorial works.; Negatives (photographs); Photographers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Howard Bond, 2018.
Inventory
- Negatives
  In some cases a pair of negatives will be found taped together; this appears to have been deliberate on the part of the photographer, and they should not be separated.
  - Portfolio I: King's Canyon, before 1974; negatives, many with notes (Box 1)
  - Portfolio IV: Huron River, before 1982; negatives, many with notes (Oversize 1)
  - Portfolio V: Colorado, before 1982; negatives, many with notes (Box 1)
  - Portfolio VI: Greek Islands, before 1985; negatives, many with notes (Box 1)
  - Portfolio VII: Proximity, before 1987; negatives, many with notes (Box 1)
  - Portfolio VIII: People and Places, negatives, many with notes (Box 1)
  - Portfolio IX: Ontario, before 1989; negatives, many with notes (Box 1)
  - Portfolio X: Contact prints, before 1990; negatives, many with notes (Oversize 1)
  - Portfolio XI: White Motif, before 1991; negatives, many with notes (Box 1)
  - Portfolio XVI: 1990s Landscapes, before 1999; negatives, many with notes (Box 1)
  - Portfolio XVII: New Zealand, before 2000; negatives, many with notes (Box 1)
  - Portfolio XVIII: Ten Cathedrals, before 2001; negatives, many with notes (Box 1)
  - Portfolio XIX: Sandstone Country, before 2002; negatives, many with notes (Box 2)
  - Portfolio XX: Abstraction, before 2003; negatives, many with notes (Box 2)
  - Portfolio XXI: Alps, before 2004; negatives, many with notes (Box 2)
  - Portfolio XXII: Aegean Light, before 2005; negatives, many with notes (Box 2)
  - Portfolio XXIII: Enigma, before 1980; negatives, many with notes; small printed booklet (Box 2)